# **Tor Francis**

Philadelphia, PA | 678-790-2697 | torfrancis447@gmail.com | linkedin.com/tor-francis | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

A highly motivated and natural people-person developer with experience designing and developing full-stack and front-end applications in Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and React. Proven ability to provide excellent end-users experience with years of experience in sales and customer service.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

AWS, REST, APIs, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Nextjs, SQL, Github, Node.js, Excel, Remedy

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Dev Hunt - Github

A job board app for candidates looking for developer jobs and companies looking to hire talent

- Implemented AWS S3 for document storage and Image storage.
- A full-stack application that follows RESTful API conventions including Authentication and Authorization.

Used front-end API for email notifications.

## Gamer's Paradise - Github | Demo

An app where users can keep track of games they would like to play

- Created a React app using Bootstrap for the CSS and React Router for client-side routing.
- Utilized a frontend API to fetch Video game data to be able to search for games currently on the market.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Bet365 Marlton, NJ

Customer Technical Support Advisor 06/2023 - Current

- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to perform web application testing, ensuring a high-quality user experience.
- Proactively troubleshoot and resolve technical issues related to software and network connectivity, ensuring minimal downtime and maximum user satisfaction.

## Ainley's Search Group

Recruiter 06/2022 - 09/2022

- Consulted with clients to obtain a precise understanding of the technical job description and requirements to fill positions with high-quality candidates in the manufacturing industry.
- Played a key role in the successful acquisition of a major chemical manufacturer by recommending exceptional talent.
- Developed a candidate tracking spreadsheet, enhancing the efficiency of the hiring process and ensuring compliance with hiring requirements.

## Frank's Recruitment Group

Philadelphia, PA

Philadelphia, PA

Recruitment Consultant 01/2022 - 05/2022

- Participate in business development to identify top accounts, target skill sets, and assess clients' ServiceNow needs.
- Negotiating employment offers for candidates in the ServiceNow industry.
- Assisted in the successful placement of candidates into client position vacancies.

# Extra Space Storage

Philadelphia, PA

District Team Lead 05/2016 - 01/2022

- Created customized Excel templates for seasonal reports, enabling efficient price analysis and data-driven decision-making.
- Implemented a digestible Excel note generator, streamlining workflow and reducing account update time by 10%.
- Managed 7 different properties, overseeing up to 800 customers, ensuring high-quality customer satisfaction.

### **EDUCATION**

# Full Stack Web Development program

Philadelphia, PA

Rigorous coursework learning and applying the fundamentals of Javascript, React, SQL, and Ruby on Rails.

10/2022 - 03/2023

# **Penn State University**

**Flatiron School** 

Philadelphia, PA

Bachelor of Science. Business Administration